# Ismail Saoudi

Cell: +1 (513) 713-4001 Email: Ismail.saoudi@icloud.com Location: Cincinnati, OH

### Social Media:

LinkedIn: Linkedin.com/in/ismail-saoudi
GitHub: Github.com/ismailsaoudi

Portfolio: https://ismailsaoudi.github.io/Portfolio\_IS/

### Desired jobs:

Junior Full Stack Web Developer Customer Success Manager Junior DevOps Engineer

### SUMMARY:

Full stack web Developer, with +10 years of IT experience driving digital transformation for Fortune 500 companies. Purposeful, customer success, profes-sional focused on building strong processes to improve Customer Adoption, Retention, and Expansion. Proven record of driving customer value, increasing retention, promoting high adoption, and driving upsell and cross-sell opportunities. Holds a master's degree in Computer Engineering. Multilingual and analytical person.

### **ACCOMPLICHEMENTS AND ABILITIES:**

- Built front-end websites from scratch, as well as using ready-made frameworks that enable you to build efficiently.
- Created full-stack single-page web applications using RESTful API routes and AJAX methods, and defined how
  front-end applications communicate with back-end applications and databases.
- Implemented structured and unstructured databases to convert static websites into dynamic websites that persist data.
- Applied the accepted and standard basics of social coding—including source control, issue tracking, and functional feedback—as part of a development community, while building an application.
- Demonstrated strong teamwork and project management skills as a collaborator and independent contributor during the development cycle of complex projects.

## **EDUCATION:**

## **Full Stack Coding**

The Ohio State University - College of Engineering - Columbus Ohio April 2022 - November 2022 Columbus, Ohio

### Bachelors in computer science

Higher institute of computer science and communication technology Sousse. September 2006 - July 2011 Sousse, Tunisia

## **CERTIFICATION:**

Cisco Certified Network Engineer: CCNA

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

### **Network Engineer**

Ransohoff January 2021 – current Cincinnati, OH

## **Application engineer**

Werth Inc.
January 2019 - November 2020 Cincinnati, OH

#### **Senior SCADA Engineer**

Cypress Creek Renewables Mai 2015- December 2018 Durham, NC

## **Integration Manger**

Huawei Technologies January 2012 - April 2015 Tunis, Tunisia

## **RELEVENT SKILLS:**

- Azure, GCP
- HTML/CSS/Git
- JavaScript
- BootstrapThe DOM
- APIs
- jQuery JSON AJAX
- Node
- ES6
- Object-oriented programming
- MySQL
- Express
- MVC paradigm

# OTHER SKILLS:

- Network Engineering
   Microsoft OS management Tools
   Cisco Certified CCNA
   Computer Science

- Telecom Industry Standards
- Rollout Management
  Blueprint interpretation
  Electronics

- Sequelize

- TestingAgile developmentProgressive Web Apps
- React
- NoSQL
- MERN Stack
- Computer scienceAzure/ GCP/ AWS
- Shell scripting
- Azure VNET
- GitHub /GitLab /Heroku
- Postman / insomnia
  SQL, MongoDB, NoSQL, SQLite
- Azure DevOps pipeline